Jinhyuk Yoon

jinhyuk.a.yoon@gmail.com https://www.jinhyukyoon.com

I am an engineer, designer and communicator creates inspirational experience and pragmatic solution. I love interacting with people through various project such as research, design, art work, and education. As using my major background and experiences, I've been trying to embrace and create meaningful work.

Professional Experience

Sovoro Jan 2018 – Apr2018

Communications Manager

Conducted UI/UX design of the service, catalog design, market research, and business activity related with public institution, educational institution, and people with hearing loss.

Korea Foundation for the Advancement of Science & Creativity

May 2016 - Jan 2018

Science Communicator

Gave talk, performed scientific street performance, and acted scientific play targeting adults as a finalist of FameLab Korea and science communicator commissioned by Ministry of Science & ICT.

Leadership Experience

POSTECH, Student Election Committee

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Chairman

Organized the student election committee and run the election for central student president.

POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering

Jan 2016 - Mar 2017

Student President

Directed student membership training, professor appreciation banquet, association program with KAIST and founded basketball and badminton club.

TEDxPOSTECH Nov 2014 - Nov 2015

Director

Organized TEDx event under the theme 'question' with 6 speakers. Conducted team building, speaker and sponsor contact, stage planning and host at the event.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

2014 - Present

Bachelor Thesis Project - Book Borrowing Robot Minor - Industrial Management Engineering Expect to graduate with *Magna Cum Laude*

Awards and Honors

Commission Letter Ministry of Science & ICT commissioned me as a science communicator	2016
Finalist Nationwide Top 11 of the 3 rd FameLab Korea	2016
Runners up Artience Creation Challenge 30x30, hosted by British Council	2017
Honorable Mention 3 Minute Science Speech Contest hosted by POSTECH	2015
Student of the Year POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering	2015, 2016
The 4th Prize The 2 nd POSTECH Hackathon	2016
National Academic Excellence Scholarship Korea Student Aid Foundation	2016 - Present
KT&G Foundation Scholarship POSTECH	2016
Jigok Scholarship POSTECH	2014 - 2016

Selected Talks

Keynote Speech, "Engineering and Science Communication", The 5th Integrated Science Leading Teacher Training, Yeongcheon	2016
Keynote Speech, "About Science Communication", National Youth Science Exploration Competition, Gyeongju	2016
Talk, "Regain the lost life", Suseong-gu Gosan Library, Daegu	2018
Talk, "Regain the lost life", KIST Science Station, Seoul	2017
Talk, "Space food", The 13th Bohyeonsan Starlight Festival, Yeongcheon	2016
Talk, "Science, Engineering and Me", Seongji Highschool, Yongin	2017

Talk, "Communicate with Science", Mulgeum High School, Yangsan	
Talk "Talk with Odd Engineering Student" Samsung Girl's High School Busan	